{
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": "001",
      "question": "What year was \"Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope\" originally released?",
      "options": ["1975", "1977", "1980", "1983"],
      "answer": "1977"
    },
    {
      "id": "002",
      "question": "Who directed \"Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope\"?",
      "options": [
        "Steven Spielberg",
        "George Lucas",
        "James Cameron",
        "Ridley Scott"
      ],
      "answer": "George Lucas"
    },
    {
      "id": "003",
      "question": "What is the name of the desert planet where Luke Skywalker is raised?",
      "options": ["Hoth", "Endor", "Tatooine", "Naboo"],
      "answer": "Tatooine"
    },
    {
      "id": "004",
      "question": "Which actor played the character Han Solo in \"Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope\"?",
      "options": [
        "Mark Hamill",
        "Harrison Ford",
        "Carrie Fisher",
        "Alec Guinness"
      ],
      "answer": "Harrison Ford"
    },
    {
      "id": "005",
      "question": "What was the original title of \"Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope\" when it was first released in 1977?",
      "options": [
        "Star Wars",
        "A New Hope",
        "The Star Wars",
        "Star Wars: The Galactic Empire"
      ],
      "answer": "The Star Wars"
    },
    {
      "id": "006",
      "question": "What is the name of Luke Skywalker's aunt?",
      "options": ["Beru", "Shmi", "Padm√©", "Leia"],
      "answer": "Beru"
    },
    {
      "id": "007",
      "question": "Who is the commander of the Death Star when it destroys Alderaan?",
      "options": [
        "Darth Vader",
        "Grand Moff Tarkin",
        "Emperor Palpatine",
        "General Veers"
      ],
      "answer": "Grand Moff Tarkin"
    },
    {
      "id": "008",
      "question": "What does Luke Skywalker use to bullseye womp rats in his T-16 back home?",
      "options": [
        "A blaster",
        "His lightsaber",
        "A grappling hook",
        "His targeting computer"
      ],
      "answer": "His targeting computer"
    },
    {
      "id": "009",
      "question": "What is the name of the Imperial protocol droid that serves the Death Star?",
      "options": ["C-3PO", "R2-D2", "K-2SO", "IG-88"],
      "answer": "C-3PO"
    },
    {
      "id": "010",
      "question": "Who says, \"Help me, Obi-Wan Kenobi. You're my only hope.\"?",
      "options": ["Princess Leia", "Queen Amidala", "Rey", "Jyn Erso"],
      "answer": "Princess Leia"
    },
    {
      "id": "011",
      "question": "What species is Chewbacca?",
      "options": ["Wookiee", "Rodian", "Twi'lek", "Mon Calamari"],
      "answer": "Wookiee"
    },
    {
      "id": "012",
      "question": "What are the odds that C-3PO claims the Millennium Falcon has successfully navigating an asteroid field?",
      "options": ["1 in 2", "1 in 1,000", "1 in 10,000", "1 in 3,720"],
      "answer": "1 in 3,720"
    },
    {
      "id": "013",
      "question": "What bounty hunter captures Han Solo on Cloud City?",
      "options": ["Boba Fett", "Greedo", "Bossk", "Dengar"],
      "answer": "Boba Fett"
    },
    {
      "id": "014",
      "question": "What type of creatures attack Luke Skywalker on Tatooine before he is saved by Obi-Wan Kenobi?",
      "options": ["Jawas", "Banthas", "Sand People", "Tusken Raiders"],
      "answer": "Sand People"
    },
    {
      "id": "015",
      "question": "Who says, \"Do or do not. There is no try.\"?",
      "options": ["Yoda", "Obi-Wan Kenobi", "Darth Vader", "Qui-Gon Jinn"],
      "answer": "Yoda"
    },
    {
      "id": "016",
      "question": "What is the name of the bar where Luke Skywalker and Obi-Wan Kenobi meet Han Solo and Chewbacca?",
      "options": [
        "The Cantina",
        "The Pub",
        "The Space Lounge",
        "The Mos Eisley Tavern"
      ],
      "answer": "The Cantina"
    },
    {
      "id": "017",
      "question": "Who destroys the first Death Star by firing a proton torpedo into its exhaust port?",
      "options": [
        "Luke Skywalker",
        "Wedge Antilles",
        "Biggs Darklighter",
        "Red Leader"
      ],
      "answer": "Luke Skywalker"
    },
    {
      "id": "018",
      "question": "What is the famous weapon used by Jedi Knights?",
      "options": ["Phaser", "Proton Torpedo", "Lightsaber", "Blaster"],
      "answer": "Lightsaber"
    },
    {
      "id": "019",
      "question": "What organization does Luke Skywalker join to fight against the Galactic Empire?",
      "options": [
        "The Rebel Alliance",
        "The Sith",
        "The First Order",
        "The Jedi Order"
      ],
      "answer": "The Rebel Alliance"
    },
    {
      "id": "020",
      "question": "Who is revealed to be Luke Skywalker's father?",
      "options": [
        "Darth Maul",
        "Darth Sidious",
        "Darth Vader",
        "Darth Tyranus"
      ],
      "answer": "Darth Vader"
    },
    {
      "id": "021",
      "question": "What is the name of the commander of the Rebel Alliance who plans the attack on the Death Star?",
      "options": [
        "Mon Mothma",
        "Admiral Ackbar",
        "General Dodonna",
        "General Jan Dodonna"
      ],
      "answer": "General Jan Dodonna"
    },
    {
      "id": "022",
      "question": "What is the call sign of Luke Skywalker during the attack on the Death Star?",
      "options": ["Red Leader", "Red Five", "Blue Squadron", "Gold Leader"],
      "answer": "Red Five"
    },
    {
      "id": "023",
      "question": "What does Han Solo say to Princess Leia just before he is frozen in carbonite?",
      "options": [
        "\"I love you.\"",
        "\"May the Force be with you.\"",
        "\"I'll be back.\"",
        "\"Never tell me the odds.\""
      ],
      "answer": "\"I love you.\""
    },
    {
      "id": "024",
      "question": "Who says, \"I find your lack of faith disturbing.\"?",
      "options": [
        "Emperor Palpatine",
        "Darth Vader",
        "Grand Moff Tarkin",
        "Count Dooku"
      ],
      "answer": "Darth Vader"
    },
    {
      "id": "025",
      "question": "What does Obi-Wan Kenobi use to disable the tractor beam on the Death Star?",
      "options": ["A lightsaber", "The Force", "A blaster", "An ion cannon"],
      "answer": "The Force"
    },
    {
      "id": "026",
      "question": "What type of starfighter does Luke Skywalker fly during the attack on the Death Star?",
      "options": ["Y-wing", "X-wing", "A-wing", "B-wing"],
      "answer": "X-wing"
    },
    {
      "id": "027",
      "question": "Who is the commander of the Imperial forces on Hoth in \"The Empire Strikes Back\"?",
      "options": [
        "Darth Vader",
        "Grand Admiral Thrawn",
        "Grand Moff Tarkin",
        "General Veers"
      ],
      "answer": "General Veers"
    },
    {
      "id": "028",
      "question": "What is the name of the smuggler who owes money to Jabba the Hutt and helps rescue Han Solo from Jabba's palace?",
      "options": ["Lando Calrissian", "Greedo", "Boba Fett", "Dash Rendar"],
      "answer": "Lando Calrissian"
    },
    {
      "id": "029",
      "question": "Who says, \"These aren't the droids you're looking for.\"?",
      "options": [
        "Han Solo",
        "Obi-Wan Kenobi",
        "Luke Skywalker",
        "Darth Vader"
      ],
      "answer": "Obi-Wan Kenobi"
    },
    {
      "id": "030",
      "question": "Who is the ruler of the Galactic Empire in \"Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope\"?",
      "options": [
        "Emperor Palpatine",
        "Darth Vader",
        "Grand Moff Tarkin",
        "General Hux"
      ],
      "answer": "Grand Moff Tarkin"
    },
    {
      "id": "031",
      "question": "What is the name of the small droid who carries the Death Star plans?",
      "options": ["BB-8", "R2-D2", "C-3PO", "K-2SO"],
      "answer": "R2-D2"
    },
    {
      "id": "032",
      "question": "What is the name of the Rebel pilot who says, \"Stay on target\" during the Death Star trench run?",
      "options": [
        "Biggs Darklighter",
        "Wedge Antilles",
        "Red Leader",
        "Gold Leader"
      ],
      "answer": "Gold Leader"
    },
    {
      "id": "033",
      "question": "What are the last words spoken in the movie?",
      "options": [
        "\"May the Force be with you.\"",
        "\"You're all clear, kid.\"",
        "\"Remember, I love you, always.\"",
        "\"Thank you.\""
      ],
      "answer": "\"Thank you.\""
    },
    {
      "id": "035",
      "question": "What is the color of Luke Skywalker's lightsaber in \"A New Hope\"?",
      "options": ["Green", "Red", "Blue", "Purple"],
      "answer": "Blue"
    },
    {
      "id": "036",
      "question": "What is the name of the planet that serves as the headquarters for the Rebel Alliance?",
      "options": ["Yavin 4", "Tatooine", "Hoth", "Endor"],
      "answer": "Yavin 4"
    },
    {
      "id": "037",
      "question": "Who says, \"I have a bad feeling about this.\"?",
      "options": ["Luke Skywalker", "Han Solo", "Princess Leia", "C-3PO"],
      "answer": "Luke Skywalker"
    },
    {
      "id": "038",
      "question": "What is the nickname given to the Millennium Falcon by Lando Calrissian?",
      "options": [
        "The Falcon",
        "The Ship of Legends",
        "The Piece of Junk",
        "Fastest hunk of junk in the galaxy"
      ],
      "answer": "Fastest hunk of junk in the galaxy"
    },
    {
      "id": "039",
      "question": "What is the name of the Rebel base on Yavin 4?",
      "options": ["Echo Base", "Base One", "Red Base", "Alliance Headquarters"],
      "answer": "Base One"
    },
    {
      "id": "040",
      "question": "What species is the character Greedo, who confronts Han Solo in the Mos Eisley Cantina?",
      "options": ["Rodian", "Twi'lek", "Mon Calamari", "Wookiee"],
      "answer": "Rodian"
    }
  ]
}
